<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<item xmlns="http://www.supermemo.net/2006/smux">
  <lesson-title>GRE词汇：《再要你命三千》</lesson-title>
  <chapter-title>List 30</chapter-title>
  <question-title>根据单词，回想词义</question-title>
  <question><span style='font-size:18; font-family:Comic Sans MS; font-weight:normal; font-style:normal; color:#550000'>agreeable</span><br/><span style='font-size:14; font-family:微软雅黑; font-weight:normal; font-style:normal; color:#000000'>[&lt;font face="Kingsoft Phonetic"&gt;E5gri:Ebl&lt;/font&gt;]</span><br/></question>
  <answer>【考法 1】  adj. 令人愉悦的：  pleasing to the mind or senses especially as according well with one's tastes or needs&lt;br&gt;【例】 Would you mind putting on some agreeable music for dinner ?  你介意为晚饭放一些令人愉快的音乐吗？‖the agreeable melancholy resulting from a sense of the transitoriness of natural beauty  因为感慨自然之美稍纵即逝而产生的令人愉悦的忧伤&lt;br&gt;【近】  congenial, delectable, delicious, delightful, dulcet, enjoyable, felicitous, gratifying,  heavenly, palatable, pleasing, satisfying, savory&lt;br&gt;【反】  abhorrent, abominable, disagreeable, disgusting, loathsome, nauseating, repellent, repugnant, repulsive, revolting 令人厌恶的&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;【考法 2】  adj. 随和的：  having an easygoing and pleasing manner especially in social situations&lt;br&gt;【例】  I have an agreeable art teacher who lets me do pretty much whatever I want.  我的艺术老师性格非常好，总是允许我去做我想做的事情。&lt;br&gt;【近】  affable, genial, good-natured, good-tempered, gracious, mellow, nice, pleasant, sweet, well-disposed&lt;br&gt;【反】  choleric, dyspeptic, fussy, grouchy, irascible, irritable, peevish, touchy  脾气不好的，易怒的&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;【考法 3】  adj. 相一致的：  being in harmony&lt;br&gt;【例】  These new security measures are not agreeable with our core concepts of personal freedom.  这些新的安保措施和我们所信仰的人身自由彼此抵触。&lt;br&gt;【近】  amicable, compatible, congenial, consistent, consonant, frictionless, kindred, unanimous, united&lt;br&gt;【反】  disagreeable, discordant, disunited, incompatible, inharmonious 不一致的&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;【记】  agree 令人同意的<br/></answer>
  <question-audio>true</question-audio>
  <modified>2011-10-14</modified>
<template-id>10030</template-id>
</item>
